SUMMARY

Full Stack Engineer with extensive experience in start-ups, serving various key roles in software development.

Advanced expertise in TypeScript and Node.js with React and GraphQL.

Demonstrated skill in architecting greenfield applications, researching emerging technologies, improving the developer experience, and working in distributed teams.

SKILLS

Languages

TypeScript, JavaScript

Frameworks

Next.js, Astro, Remix, Gatsby, Nest.js

Frontend

HTML5, CSS3, React, Urql, Apollo Client, Styled-Components, Tailwind CSS, Visx, D3, Recharts, Framer Motion, Storybook, React-Three-Fiber, React-Window, Radix, Headless UI, Reakit, Redux, Slate, Prism

Backend

Node.js, Cloudflare Workers, Serverless, GraphQL, tRPC, Prisma, Nexus, Postgres, MongoDB, Redis, Apollo Server, Express, Socket.io, NextAuth

Tooling + Services

Linux, Mac, Git, VSCode, Figma, Zeplin, SourceTree, Webpack, pnpm workspaces, GraphQL-Codegen, Terraform, CDKTF, Turborepo, Docker, GitHub Actions, AWS, Vercel, Netlify, Cloudflare, Upstash, NeonDB, Confluence, Amplitude, Notion, Jira, Google Analytics, Segment, Sentry, Postmark, Octokit, Algolia, Stripe, Twilio, Stellate, Cloudinary, Playwright, Cypress, Jest, Changesets, Chromatic

Concepts + Misc.

SEO, A11y, I18n, ISR, SSR, Atomic Design, JWT, Authorization, Image Optimization, Lighthouse, Code-splitting, DB Seeding, DB Normalization, GraphQL APQ, CRDTs, Windowing, IP Blacklisting, Rate Limiting, Concurrency, API Caching, Monorepos

View this resume online at: resume.leedavidcs.dev



David Lee

Staff Software Engineer

- jobs.lee.david.cs@gmail.com
- github.com/leedavidcs
- in linkedin.com/in/leedavidcs
- makepurple.com/leedavidcs

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



Openbase (shut-down)

Staff Frontend Engineer

Apr 2021 - Present

- Proposed then executed a gradual migration strategy to port the frontend from a SPA-Parcel app to Next.js, Apollo, Styled-Components, Storybook and Codegen.
- ▶ Improved performance, ally and SEO to boost Lighthouse scores from 20 to 90.
- Architected the frontend application and implemented many features with Next.js, Apollo, Styled-Components, Storybook, Codegen and Tailwind CSS.
- Created an Algolia-Apollo interoperability module to power Openbase's search, that populated @apollo/client's normalized cache.
- Pitched and executed on experiments in product feature ideation to drive user aguisition and retention.
- ▶ Mentored such topics including Next.js, GraphQL + Apollo, Storybook, and more.
- ▶ Authored a split-testing framework that integrated with Google Analytics and Amplitude to a/b test by segmenting users by percentage or special conditions.
- Created serverless functions to reroute traffic from old sites and generate custom README badges with metrics from Openbase for package maintainers.



@pluv/io

Open Source (npm)

Aug 2022 - Present

- Created E2E type-safe, real-time packages for Node.js and Cloudflare Workers.
- ▶ Built with support for automatic type safety, authentication, custom events, rooms, awareness + presence and CRDT storage (with yjs).
- ► Configured git and npm management with Commitizen, Changeset, Renovate, Kodiak and GitHub Actions.
- Added E2E tests with Playwright, simulating runs on singular and distributed Node.is servers, and Cloudflare Worker durable objects.
- Implemented Vercel-style multi-project deployments for websocket servers as a GitHub app, using CDKTF/Terraform, AWS (S3, SQS, ECR, Lambda) and wrangler.



MakePurple

Project Owner

Sep 2021 - Present

- ▶ Built with Next.js, NextAuth, Prisma, Nexus, Apollo Server, Styled-Components, Twin.Macro, TailwindCSS, Urql, Storybook, PlanetScale, Upstash, Cloudinary, Postmark, Pusher, Octokit, Figma, Pnpm workspaces and Turborepo.
- ► Authored an internal CSS-in-JS library for emails in React, a rich text editor with Slate, heat-maps with Visx, a type-safe GraphQL client for Octokit, and more.
- ► Improved accessibility with support for screen-readers and keyboard navigation with Radix and Headless UI.
- Implemented GraphQL resolvers for: activity feeds, GitHub follows, Cloudinary image uploads, Pusher real-time chat, GitHub skill and user search, connection suggestions, notifications, nested commenting, and CRUD with Nexus + Prisma.

EDUCATION

BS in Computer Science

University of California, San Diego

Graduated: June 2017

View this resume online at: resume.leedavidcs.dev

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)



Toastel (shut-down)

Senior Full Stack Engineer

Jan 2020 - Mar 2021

- Designed in Figma, and created an atomic design system without using any uitoolkits, while improving accessibility and minimizing client bundle size.
- Authored an internal charting library with Visx, a data-grid library with React-Window, responsive emails with Mjml, animations with Framer-Motion, and more.
- ► Created several GraphQL-Nexus plugins to rate-limit fields, validate inputs, and prevent malicious queries with complexity and depth limits.
- ▶ Coded over 300 components and 400 stories on Storybook, with snapshot tests.
- ► Achieved 95-100 on all Google Lighthouse metrics (excluding PWA).
- ▶ Implemented JWTs with refresh-tokens, blacklists and retries with Redis + Apollo.
- ► Implemented GraphQL resolvers for: full-text search with Algolia, emails with Nodemailer, subscriptions and payouts with Stripe, presigned URL uploads with S3, localized timezones with Google Maps, and CRUD with Nexus + Prisma.



Onfleet

Full Stack Engineer

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

- Migrated the AngularJS + ES5 frontend to React, Styled-Components and TypeScript with snapshot testing through Jest + Storybook.
- Proposed then directed the migration of the CoffeeScript + Restify backend monolith to TypeScript, Apollo Server and Serverless-Http that would allow for incremental adoption for frontend and mobile teams.
- ▶ Rewrote both the Stripe billing and the Twilio voice and SMS proxying services to support more features, be more declarative and be more testable.



Outward (acquired)

Senior Software Engineer

Jan 2018 - Jan 2019

- ▶ Implemented all client-side features for a 3D monogramming web-app that supports more use-cases and produces higher-fidelity product images than Adobe's Scene7 for Williams-Sonoma (built with React, TypeScript, JSS, Apollo, GraphQL, Pixi, Babylon).
- Mentored Junior Frontend Engineers; worked with project managers in driving requirements and timelines; interfaced directly with clients to assist integration; and organized and led meetings with QA, graphics and the dev-ops teams to coordinate successful releases and milestones.
- Created a RESTful service for Bassett Furniture's new consumer site, including customer/designer interactions and authentication (built with TypeScript + Koa).
- ► Architected new client site with TypeScript, React, Redux Observable and JSS.
- ▶ Authored an internal library to gradually migrate a legacy vanilla ES5 app to React, while increasing test coverage from 0 to 60%.
- Set-up a CI/CD pipeline using TravisCI, SonarQube, Jest and ESLint.



Newport Asia

Contract Software Engineer

Jun 2016 - Dec 2017



Bosera Funds

Intern Software Engineer

Jun 2015 - Jun 2016